Like I said, welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer where we open up with the ten
commandments that God commanded for the
whole world to keep. Brother Tanzel,
>> and God spake all these words, saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which hath brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shall have no
other gods before me. Thou shalt not
make to thee any graven in image or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above, or that is in the earth beneath,
or that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shall not bow down thyself to them,
nor serve them. For I the Lord thy God
am a jealous God, visiting the
iniquities of the fathers upon the
children, unto the third and fourth
generation of them that hate me, and
showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain. For the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that take of his name
in vain. Remember the Sabbath day to
keep it holy. Six days shall thou labor
and do all thy work. But the seventh day
he is the Sabbath of the Lord thy God.
In it thou shall not do any work. Thou
nor thy son, nor thy daughter, thy man's
servant, nor thy maid servant, nor thy
cattle, nor that stranger that is within
thy gates. For in six days the Lord made
heaven and earth, the sea, and all that
in the midst, and rested the seventh
day. Wherefore the Lord blessed the
Sabbath day, and hollowed it. Honor thy
father and thy mother, that thy days may
be long upon the land which the Lord thy
God giveth thee. Thou shall not kill,
thou shall not commit adultery, thou
shall not steal. Thou shall not bear
false witness against thy neighbor. Thou
shall not cover thy neighbor's house.
Thou shalt not cover thy neighbor's
wife, nor his man's servant, nor his
maid servant, nor his ax, nor his ass,
nor anything that is thy neighbors. We
read Exodus 21-17. And may the Lord have
a blessing to the reading of his words.
In Jesus name we pray. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> So here on question and answer, you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the long scripture
questions as well as the vague questions
and questions of debate. We are not here
to debate. We are here to spread the
true gospel of Jesus. So please be as
direct as possible with your questions
so we can be as direct as possible with
our answers out of the King James Bible.
No other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also, keep
in mind this is a live stream, so feel
free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just ask
that you keep your questions to a two
scripture maximum. Let me introduce to
you the family that'll be on the panel
this evening. We got brother Julius.
>> Good evening everybody.
>> Brother Jerome, grace in peace. Brother
Dre,
>> good evening.
>> Brother Tanzel,
>> Sister Deborah,
>> good evening.
>> Brother Sean,
>> And we have the guest caller with us.
And I'm brother Cornell. What is our
first question, Sister De?
>> Yes, there are several held over
questions that will be answered first
before getting into tonight's Q&A.
Navy doc says many people in IoG are in
a hotels
on the Sabbath day that have free food.
I know what Exodus 35 verse3 says.
However,
how do we educate the people that
someone is working to prepare that food?
Should you be eating food that someone
else cooked on the Sabbath day? Should
you be getting the cold foods like milk,
cereal, and fruit that someone put out
on the Sabbath day? Is this still
causing someone to work on the Sabbath
day?
>> All right. So, on the Sabbath day,
staying at a hotel and they got foods to
choose from. Guest call them.
Well, why don't you go read what he
quoted?
>> 35 and3, right? Exodus
>> 35 verse3.
>> All right.
And ye shall kindle no fire throughout
your inhabitations upon the Sabbath day.
>> Now, the whole thing is we're not kind
of fire. And for the people working in
the hotels,
they we are not causing them to work.
They working anyway. But I'm But I tell
you something.
We don't we not only don't only go in
the hotels, we also are on planes on the
Sabbath day. We also are driving vans
and we have to buy gas to f to to uh put
in the van on the Sabbath day.
And why is because for all of those
reasons we are out there taking care of
the Lord's business. Now let's go into
Matthews the 12th chapter and read 1-5.
Matthews 12 1-5.
At that time Jesus went on the Sabbath
day through the corn and his disciples
were a hunger and began to pluck the
ears of corn and to eat. But when the
Pharisees saw, they said unto him,
Behold, thy disciples do that which is
not lawful to do upon the Sabbath day.
But he said unto them,
>> now what? What it say? Your disciples do
that which is not lawful on the Sabbath
day. Who are you? The Pharisees said
that. Right.
>> Right.
>> Let's let Jesus answer. Go ahead.
>> But he said unto them, "Have ye not read
what David did when he was a hunger and
they that were with him? And how he
entered into the house of God, and did
eat the showbread, which was not lawful
for him to eat, neither for them which
were with him, but only for the priests.
Or he or have you not read in the law
how that on the Sabbath days the priests
in the temple profane the Sabbath and
are blameless? But I say unto you that
in this place is one greater than the
temple. But if you had known what his
>> That's it, brother. Hold it there.
The whole thing is the Lord let you know
David and his men went and ate ate the
showbread which is for the peace because
there was a hunger. Then again too the
uh uh the the the priest uh uh defile
the Sabbath day every Sabbath day and
are blameless.
>> Why is that? Because for the same reason
we are blameless. Because we are out
there taking care of the Lord's
business.
>> Yes.
>> If we have to eat sometime in a hotel,
if we have to fly fly on a plane where
you got uh uh uh uh pilots working and
you got uh uh uh what do you call these
you know uh people that's on the planes?
>> Flight attendants.
>> Flightend,
>> right? Now either we have to go and buy
gas from a gas station that you have
people operating. We are not out there
doing our pleasure. We are taking care
of the Lord's business. And he showed us
just like David was blameless for eating
showbread on the priest. And just like
the priests kindle the fire every day,
even on the Sabbath day, and do other
things that the Lord uh to take care of
the Lord's business, and they are
blameless.
And if it's was good, if it was allowed
then, it is allowed now.
So we ought to take care of the Lord's
business instead of sitting at at home
doing nothing on the Sabbath day. That's
all I have to say.
>> All right. I hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Andre Jr. asks, "If you know
someone that is a lesbian and is having
a baby, are you able to attend the baby
shower?"
>> What about the baby shower guest caller?
>> Well, I say uh that's up to you.
All right.
>> All right. We hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Starshima McGregory asks, "If
a teenager commits suicide and he or she
didn't know the law, will God forgive?"
Well, we know that God is very merciful,
very kind, and we also know that u sadly
to say that suicide even amongst the
young folks has really increased.
And we encourage people to call 988 if
that is what is on your mind. But let's
go first um to Matthew 19.
Matthew 19.
And when you get there, brother, let's
read that one verse 26 because we know
sometime people are going through it,
whether young or old, but we'd like for
you to remember this. Whatever you're
going through, Matthew 19 and 26. Go
ahead.
>> But Jesus beheld them and said unto
them, "With men this is impossible, but
with God all things are possible."
>> So all things are possible with God. No
matter what you might be going through,
don't give up on him. Go to 1
Corinthians the 10th chapter. 1
Corinthians 10. And we got one more
after that. 1 Corinthians the 10th
chapter.
Because sometimes you do need help
mentally with what you might be going
through. 1 Corinthians 10 and read that
verse 13. Go ahead.
For there have no temptation taken, but
you such as is common to man. But God is
faithful, who will not suffer you to be
tempted above that ye are able, but will
with the temptations also make a way to
escape that ye may be able to bear.
>> The Lord is letting us know it's a lot
of trials and tribulations going on with
people. But the Lord say, hey, he won't
put on you more than you can bear and
also can provide a way for you to
escape. So please don't give up on God.
Last scripture, 2 Corinthians
5, because they asked about uh in that
question too, will he or she be
forgiven? Let's see what that second
Corinthians 5 and 10 says. Go ahead,
brother. For we must all appear before
the judgment seat of Christ, that
everyone may receive the things done in
his body according to that he have done
whether it be good or bad.
>> So that is uh the book that is written
as far as salvation and forgiveness.
Hey, God is merciful. You sit on the
mercy seat and everybody got to go to
the judgment seat of Christ. Anybody
else? That's all I got.
All right, we hope that answered your
question there. And to the young people,
stay strong with God. Moving on, Sister
Deb.
>> Moving on. Ha J Israel asked question
from John 4 6-12.
In verse 12, he asks,
"Why did the Samrian woman say our
father Jacob if she wasn't an
Israelite?"
>> All right. If she wasn't Israelite, then
John 4:6 and through 12 shed some light.
Brother Julius,
>> let's read the scripture.
This was a Hamite, a Samaritan woman. Go
ahead, Tangel. St. John 4 6-12 quickly.
Go ahead. Now Jacob's well was there.
Jesus therefore being weary with his
journey set thus on the well. And it was
about the sixth hour. But there cometh a
woman of Samaria to draw water. And
Jesus said unto her, give me to drink.
For his disciples were gone away unto
the city to buy meat. Then said the
woman of Samaria unto him, how is it
that thou being a Jew askest, drink of
me, which am a woman of Samaria? For the
go ahead, finish it.
>> For the Jews have no dealings with the
Samaritans. Now,
>> now
she was not, if she was an Israelite,
she wouldn't even ask that question. How
is it that you being a Jew have dealing
with uh the Samaritan,
but the Sam Jews have no dealing with
the Samaritan?
Right? So that's why she asked the
question, how is it that you being a Jew
uh ask me a woman of Samaria? We don't
have no dealing with the Jews.
>> Right?
>> Because sisters and brothers,
she was not original inhabitant of the
land. Let's go to second Kings the 17th
chapter.
>> Did you want me to finish it?
>> Did uh did we finish it?
>> We stopped at verse nine.
>> That was that's all we needed.
>> Okay.
>> That's that's all we needed. Thank you,
brother. That's all we needed. Let's go
to 2 Kings chapter 17 and show you why
she said that. 2 Kings 17. And when you
get it, brother, start reading at verses
five and six.
>> Second Kings 17.
>> And she was a Samaritan which was which
was an inhabitant of Samaria, the
northern tribe of Israel after the
split.
Go ahead, read in verse 5.
>> Then the kings of Assyria came up
throughout all the land and went up to
Samaria and besieged it three years.
And in the ninth year of Hosa the king
of Assyria took Samaria and carried
Israel away unto Syria and placed him in
Halah
and in Habore by the river of Gan and in
the city of the Mes. So now in the ninth
year, the king of Assyria
took out they besieged uh uh uh the
northern tribe of Assyria and they
conquered them and they took out the
original Samaritans which were
Israelites.
And then and what did he do? He placed
them in Halah and Hore by the river of
Goan and in the city of the Mes right
now. So the original inhabitants, the
real Israelites are taken out of the
land and other nations are put in the
land of Samaria. So now skip down to
verse 23 and we going to read here and
continue reading verse 23. Go ahead.
Unto the Lord remove Israel out of his
sight as he had said by all his servants
the prophet. So it was Israel cave away
out of their own land to Assyria unto
this day.
>> And then what happened? And that the
king of Assyrius brought men from
Babylon unto Couta and from Aba and from
Hath and from Safi Saf Saffraim and
place them in the cities of Samaria
instead of the children of Israel.
>> That's how the woman got there because
her ancestors were imported from another
land into the land of Samaria. So when
you are imported in a in a land you
don't know the land. So what has to
happen? Go ahead.
And so it was at the beginning of their
dwelling there that they feared not the
Lord. So therefore the Lord sent lions
among them which slew some of them.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Wherefore they spake to the king of
Assyria, saying the nations which thou
hast removed and placed in the cities of
Samaria. Know not the manner of the God
of the land.
>> Therefore we have sent lions among them.
And behold they slay them because they
know not the manner of the God of the
land.
>> So what did he come up? What did the
king of Assyria come up with? Go ahead.
>> Then the king of Assyria commanded,
saying, "Carry there the one of the
priests whom ye brought from this, and
let them go and dwell there, and let him
teach them the manner of the God of the
land."
>> So now that woman of Samaria, her
ancestors were taught by one of the
priests of Israel. That's why she said,
"Our father Jacob dwelt in this land."
Because if you are in a land and you
taking another people's culture over the
time as pro as time pro progresses,
you're going to assume that that is your
land and that is your ancestry. But it's
not. So that's why she said what she
said to Jesus. How is it that you being
a Jew talking to me a woman of Samaria?
For the Jews have no dealings with the
Samaritans because she was not an
original uh Samaritan. uh she was not an
original inhabitant of Samaria. She was
in her ancestors was imported there by
the king of Assyria and that's why she
said uh our father Jacob
>> because the priests taught those people
that
>> right?
>> So in order to be called by a land you
have to be taught by the original people
of that land. I hope that helped.
>> All right. Thank you.
>> Yes sir. Go ahead. guest call.
>> Let me show you what Jesus said when he
was here. Go to Matthew's 10 10th
chapter. Read verse one and then skip
down and read verses four and five.
>> Take your guest caller. Matthew 10.
>> Mhm.
>> One verse.
And when he had called unto them his 12
disciples, he gave them power against
unclean spirits to cast them out and to
heal all manner of sickness and all
manner of disease.
>> Now skip down to four and get the
commandment here. Four and five.
>> Simon the Canaanite and Judas Escariat
who also betrayed him.
>> These four and five.
>> Yes.
Well,
>> yeah, that's it. Maybe
>> where he told him to go not in the way.
>> That's verse five.
>> Yeah. Five. Then go.
Read it.
>> So these 12 Jesus sent forth and
commanded them, saying, "Go not into the
way of the Gentiles, and into any city
of the Samaritans, into ye not,
but go rather to the lost sheep of the
house of Israel.
So now if he told them not to go into
the way of the gentile nor any city in
Samaria but go rather to the lost sheep
of the house of Israel that tell you
then that the people in Samaria was not
Israelites.
>> Yes sir.
>> All right. Thank you for that add on.
Hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next question.
>> Next one. Yazi Ya Monae asks, "Is there
any meeting if we have dreams of loved
ones that passed away?"
Right, brother Dre? Dreams of loved ones
that have passed away. What you say?
>> Yeah. Well, is there any meaning to it?
That's something that that I can't
answer straight out like that. But
dreams, let let's go to a couple of
scriptures. Let's go to Ecclesiastics 5.
Ecclesiastics 5. And we're going to read
verse three. Ecclesiastics
5 and verse three.
Read that when you get it, brother.
>> For a dream cometh through the multitude
of business, and a fool's voice is known
by multitude of words. So you can have
your loved ones on your mind and you can
dream about them. Matter of fact, I
dreamed about my mother last night.
But you know what it was about? I
couldn't tell you. Does it have any
meaning? Did it have any meaning for me?
No. But what I will say is this. Let's
go to Ecclesiastics 9.
Because some believe that our loved ones
speak to us through our dreams. Let's go
to Ecclesiastics 9 and I want you to
read verse uh 5 and then I want you to
skip to verse 10. Ecclesiastics 9 verse
5.
For the living know that they should
die, but the dead know not anything,
neither have they any more reward, for
the memory of them is forgotten. So our
loved ones are not
anywhere talking to us whether it be in
a dream, in a vision. And there are
those that pour out libations to their
ancestors and call on them as if they're
raising them. But what they are dealing
with is familiar spirits.
But verse 5 says, "For the living know
that they shall die, but the dead know
not anything, neither have they anymore
a reward, for the memory of them is
forgotten, meaning they have no memory."
Then verse 10, go ahead.
>> Whatsoever thy hand findeth to do, do it
with thy might. For there is no work,
nor device, nor knowledge, nor wisdom in
the grave whether thou goest. So there
is no work nor knowledge nor wisdom in
the grave whether you go. So your loved
ones are not speaking to you through
dreams
because they are at rest. Now let's go
to uh Jeremiah 23. I want to look at
something there and then I'm going to
let it go. There's a multitude. The
scripture says your young men will dream
dreams and have visions, but at the end
of the day, we talking about our loved
ones that passed.
Uh Jeremiah 23 28 and 29.
Read that when you get it, brother.
>> The prophet that hath a dream, let him
tell a dream. And he that have my word,
let him speak my word faithfully. What
is the chaff to the wheat? Sayeth the
Lord. Mhm.
>> Not my word like as a fire, sayeth the
Lord, and like a hammer that break the
rock in pieces.
>> So, we abide by the word of God. We
believe in the word of God. And the word
of God says that the dead will be raised
at the last day. They're not coming to
us, speaking to us in dreams and
visions.
That's all I got.
>> Right. That brother Dre should put
all the crystal ball people out of
business with them scriptures you just
read, brother.
All right, I hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
>> Next one. Detroit. Troy Price says in
Luke 20:36,
it says that we will be equal to the
angels, the children of God. Are the
angels God?
That is being said, a part of a God's
family.
>> All right, brother Jerome, go ahead.
>> Um, no, it's not it's not talking uh the
way you worded the question. Um, you
mixing precepts and and we going to show
you. Let's let's read the verse that you
gave that Luke 20 and 36.
Neither can they die anymore. For they
are equal unto the angels and are the
children of God being the children of
the resurrection.
Okay. So you talking about the children
of the resurrection. Okay. Being equal
to the angels in in in the sense that
they're not going to be able to die when
they get that body at the resurrection.
Angels can't die. And those that come up
in the resurre first resurrection, they
ain't going to be able to die either.
Actually, second resurrection, they
ain't going to die no more either. You
know, but when you try to compare that
and say, well, the angels
are God. Because you using the term
equal in that verse, it's not talking
about the angels are equal to God in
that they got power. All power like God
got.
The angels, you know, are not equal to
God in that sense. All right?
>> But when these people that be worthy
that come up in that first resurrection,
they'll be equal to God
and the angels still won't be equal to
God. Even though those in the
resurrection can't die,
and the angels can't die, but the angels
ain't equal to God cuz they can't die.
Okay?
>> Right.
>> All right. So now um let's go to um the
Hebrews 2.
Go to Hebrews 2 and we going to read
verse 5 and then we're going to go to 1
Corinthians the 6th chapter after that
cuz the Lord he want he he want this man
to to be equal with him. If he be worthy
enough to come up in that resurrection,
you know, cuz he done been righteous in
the eyes of God,
he going to be equal with God. Okay. So,
uh, Hebrews 2 and five, read it.
>> For unto the angels, have he not put in
subjection the world to come whereof we
speak?
>> All right. So the angels ain't going to
have what the Lord gonna give this man
if he be so blessed. All right.
>> Now let's go to first Corinthians 6 and
read verse two and three and that'll be
it.
>> Do you not know that the saints shall
judge the world? And if the world shall
be judged by you, are you unworthy to
judge the smallest matter?
>> The angels ain't going to judge the
world even though they can't die. All
right. But keep reading.
>> Know ye not that we shall judge angels.
>> How much more things that pertain to
this life?
>> Yeah. He going to put you over all the
works of God want to put man over all
the works of his hands including angels.
That's all.
>> All right. That that um thank you for
that brother. As we go on to that next
question, Sister Deborah.
>> Uh yes. Shanquila Aru Joby asks, "Should
we please people?" Galatians 1 verse 10
raises the question of whether we aim to
please man or God, while First
Corinthians 9:1 19 discusses Paul
becoming a slave to win many.
>> All right. Need a little light on that,
Dre. What you say?
>> Yeah. Let's go to uh Galatians 1 and uh
let's read that verse 10. Uh brother
Tanzel, when you get it, go ahead. Paul
was a persecutor of the church and when
he got knocked down and and he was told
that it was Jesus whom he was
persecuting, Paul was converted and he
became a servant.
And he wasn't about trying to please
those that he was rolling with at the
time that rejected Jesus. Paul preached
the gospel. Verse 10. Go ahead, brother.
>> What do I now persuade men or God? But
do I seek to please men? For if I yet
please men, I should not be the servant
of Christ.
>> Yeah. Paul said if he pleased men, he's
not going to be a servant of Christ. So
Paul was set on pleasing God, not man.
You know, he wasn't trying to tell men
what they wanted to hear. Let's go to
Romans, the first chapter, and look at
something here. Romans 1, and we're
going to read verses 16 and 17.
Paul preached the gospel of Christ. He
preached it to the Gentiles as well as
to Israel. Yeah,
>> but
uh Romans 1:1617.
Go ahead, brother.
>> I am not ashamed of the gospel of
Christ. For it is the power of God and
to salvation to everyone that believe
>> true first and also to the Greek.
For therein is the righteousness of God
revealed from faith to faith, as it is
written, the just shall live by faith.
>> That's right. the just shall live by
faith. But let's go to your other
scripture. 1 Corinthians 1, I mean 1
Corinthians 9, and we going to pick it
up at verse 16.
You You got 19 on here. We going to read
verse 16. 1 Corinthians 9 and let's read
16. Go ahead.
>> Well, though I preach the gospel, I have
nothing to glory.
For necessity is laid upon me. Yeah, woe
is unto me if I preach not the gospel.
>> That's right. Go ahead.
>> Well, if I do this thing willfully, I
have a reward. But if against my will a
dispensation of the gospel is committed
unto me,
>> what what is my reward then? Verily that
when I preach the gospel, I may make the
gospel of Christ without charge, that I
abuse not my power in the gospel.
>> Go ahead.
>> For though I be free from all men, yet
have I made myself servant unto all that
I might gain the more.
>> So Paul is preaching the gospel and he
is preaching the gospel that he might
gain all. So when he say he's making
himself a servant to all, he is serving
the Lord and preaching the gospel.
Go ahead, brother.
And unto the Jews I became as a Jew,
that I might gain the Jews to them that
are under the law, as under the law,
that I might gain them that are under
the law.
>> Skip down to verse 23 and read that, and
that'll be it.
and this I do for the gospel's sake,
that I might be partakers thereof with
you.
>> So Paul wasn't uh flip-flopping and
being uh one way with men and one way,
you know, with God, trying to please
men. He was preaching the gospel of
Christ,
>> right?
>> That's what Paul did.
So he he looked to persuade men of the
gospel.
That's what he was doing. I hope that
helped.
>> All right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answered the question. As we move on,
>> moving on. Brit Brett wants help to
explain John 14:E2.
She says, "My friend thinks what Jesus
said means people will be in heaven. I
tried to tell him this was a parable.
body in heaven. Brother Julius, what you
say? It's
>> not a parable. It is a statement of
truth and and future. Let's read that.
Uh St. John 14 and let's read verse two,
but we're going to read verse two and
three. St. John 14 is a continuation of
St. John the 13th chapter. Go ahead,
Tenzel.
In my father's house are many mansions.
And if it were not so, I would have told
you. But I go to prepare a place for
you.
>> Yes.
>> And if I go and prepare a place for you,
I will come again and receive you unto
myself that where I am, there you may be
also.
>> And that is absolutely true. And that is
what Jesus saying. But let's read St.
John 13 and let's read verse 33.
And Jesus is talking to his disciples
again. Go ahead,
>> little children, yet a little while I am
with you, and ye shall seek me. And as I
said unto the Jews, whether I go, ye
cannot come. So now I say to you,
>> like I told the Jews, I'm telling you,
where I go, you cannot come. So when he
said in St. John the 14th chapter and
verse two, in my father's house are many
masters, but you can't get to the
father's kingdom until you get through
the son's kingdom. Let me tell you what
I'm talking about. Let's go to
Revelation.
Let's go to Revelation
the uh 21st chapter, the third chapter,
Revelation 3. And let's look at what
Jesus said. Revelation 3 and 21.
Revelation 3. And this is one of the
many promises of God. Revelation
3 and 21. Go ahead.
>> To him that overcometh will I grant to
sit with me in my throne. Even as I also
overcame am and am sat down with my
father in his throne. So now Jesus never
promised you the father's throne.
Jesus promised that you going to sit
with him and his throne and where he
going to be. Right?
>> So now when Jesus come at the seventh
trumpet and set on the throne of David
which is his still his throne you get
you are so blessed to be in the first
resurrection you going to rule and reign
with him in his throne. Now let's go to
St. John the third chapter.
Back up to St. John the 3r chapter
and let's read 12-13
St. John 3 12 and 13. So he told you in
my father's house are many mansions
and he said I go to prepare a place for
you in my father's house. I didn't
promise you you go with me up there. St.
John 3 and read verse 12 and 13. Go
ahead brother. If I have told you
earthly things, and ye believe not,
well, how shall ye believe if I tell you
of heavenly things?
>> Go ahead.
>> And no man have ascended up to heaven,
but he that came down from heaven, even
the son of man which is in heaven.
>> So ain't nobody in heaven. The Bible
does not teach going to heaven. The
Bible teaches thy kingdom come. And when
the kingdom come, talking about the
father's kingdom, there will be no more
flesh and blood on this earth. It's only
going to be immortals on this earth. But
during Jesus' reign, it's still going to
be flesh and blood on this earth. That's
a whole another lesson for another time.
But it's going to be ruled over by
spirit beings. And that's what we're
working on right now, trying to get
ourselves ready so we can qualify
ourselves for Jesus Christ kingdoms that
he going to rule for a thousand years.
and we gonna reign with him and sit with
him and his throne on the earth. And
then a thousand years later, the father
brings new Jerusalem down the house of
many matches. And then that's where that
St. John 14:2 kicks in.
>> I hope that helped. Anybody else?
>> Yes, sir. Even in the Lord's prayer, thy
kingdom come.
>> Yes. Call.
>> I want I want to throw a couple things.
He said, "I go to prepare a place for
you,
>> and if I go, I will come again and
receive you unto myself."
>> Right?
>> Uh and and then he said that uh uh in
Hebrews, I think the 10th chapter where
he went and prepared uh uh uh uh the
people that uh uh that's on this earth,
he went and prepared for them a city or
they are strangers and pilgrims on this
earth. Can somebody find that right
quick?
>> That's Hebrews the 11th chapter.
>> Yeah. and see if you can read the people
that uh said it is strangers.
>> Verse six,
>> that's you can pick up. I
>> guess we can pick it up verse 13.
>> 13.
>> Okay, start reading it. These all died
in faith, not having received the
promises, but having seen them a far
off, and were persuaded of them, and
embraced them, and confessed that they
were strangers and pilgrims on the
earth.
>> Go ahead.
For they that say such things declare
plainly that they seek a country. And
truly if they had been mindful of that
that country from whence they came out
they might have had opportunity to have
returned.
But now
they desire a better country that is in
heavenly wherefore God is not ashamed to
be called their God for heath prepared
for them a city.
>> Yes sir. Now, let's go and see what he
going to do with that city that he
prepared them a place in. Go to
Revelation 21 and read uh uh and start
reading that verse one.
>> And I saw a new heaven and a new earth,
for the first heaven and the first earth
were passed away, and there was no more
sea. And I, John, saw the holy new
Jerusalem coming down from heaven,
prepared as a bride adorned for her
husband. And I heard
is coming. Ain't that correct?
>> Yes, sir.
>> The BS are done. Let's see what where
it's going to end up at. Keep reading.
>> I heard a great voice out of heaven
saying, "Behold, the tabernacle of God
is with men, and he will dwell with
them, and they should be his people, and
God himself shall be with them, and be
their God,
and God shall walk away all
tabernacle. God is with man. because he
brought it down.
Prepared as a bride are done for her
husband. That's why I say if I go if I
go to prepare a place for you, if I go
again, I will come again receive to
myself. And New Jerusalem is this is
this father's house of many mentions
coming down to us. We ain't going up to
it. That's all I have to say.
>> Thank you. Amen. That's what it says.
>> All right. Thy kingdom come. Just like
it's in the Lord's Prayer.
All right, we're going to move on to our
next question. Sister Deborah with a
time check.
>> Yeah. Yes. The time is A12. Uh Pauline R
wants an explanation on Micah 3 2 and 3.
Is this talking about bad doctrine or
witchcraft?
>> All right. Micah three.
And we're going to pick it up at that
verse two and three. And when you get
there, brother, go ahead. And the guest
caller will take it from there. Micah 3
2 and three.
Who hate the good and love the evil who
pluck off their skin from off them and
their flesh from off their bones. Who
also eat the flesh of my people and flay
their skin from off them. And they break
their bones and chop them in pieces. as
for the pot and as flesh within the
cauldron.
>> That's bad doctor. Skip down and read
verses 6 and 7.
5 through 7 rather 5-7.
>> Thus sayeth the Lord concerning the
prophets that make my people heir, they
bite with their teeth and cry peace. And
he that putteth not into their mouths,
they even prepare war against them.
>> So therefore night shall be unto you,
and they shall not have a vision. It
shall be dark unto you, that ye shall
not divine, and the sun shall go down
over the prophets, and the day shall be
dark over them. Then shall the seers be
ashamed and the devaners confounded.
Yeah, they shall all cover their lips
for there is no answer of God.
So that's talking about bad doctrine.
They teach you that bad doctrine and
Lord ain't going to answer.
And so what they doing is they abusing
and using the people just like chopping
them up and eating them. It's not
witchcraft. They just teach them bad
doctrine.
That's all I have to say.
All right. Hope that answered your
question. Next question.
>> Next question. Mr. Lean Perry wants you
to explain Proverbs 3 verse 15.
It's called is called wisdom. A she help
him understand.
>> All right. Wisdom is called a she.
Brother Jerome.
There's um a metaphor um that uh
referring to the word of God, the
knowledge of God, the understanding of
God. Okay, it proceeded from the mouth
of God,
the Godhead.
Okay. So, uh let's go to Proverbs
chapter 1
and read verse 20 and 21.
Wait, go ahead.
>> Wisdom crith without thou. She utter her
voice in the streets. She crith of the
chief place of concourse. Uhhuh. to it
as a she just like in your question. So
I don't want to uh leave out the verse
you gave in your question. So let's read
that. Proverbs 3:15.
>> Go ahead.
>> She is more precious than rubies,
and all the things thou canest desire
are not to be compared unto her. I can
tell how you asked the question that you
understand is talking about wisdom. All
right. So now let's go back to that uh
first chapter again, brother Tanzel,
and read that 20 and 21 again.
Wisdom crith with thou. She utter her
voice in the streets. She crith into the
chief place of concourse. In the
openings of the gate, in the city she
uttered her words, saying,
>> she utter her what? Her words.
>> All right,
go right into the second chapter
and uh read verse 1-5.
My son, if thou will receive my words
and hide my commandments with thee
words involve the commandments of God,
don't they?
>> Go ahead.
>> So that thou incline thy ear unto
wisdom.
>> Cuz his commandments is wisdom.
Them commandments are get lead you into
eternal life if you keep them.
>> Right.
>> Go ahead. That's verse. Go ahead.
>> And apply thy heart to understanding.
Uh-huh.
>> But yeah, if thou criest after
knowledge, and lift up thy voice for
understanding,
if thou seekest her as silver, and
searches for her as for hidden
treasures,
and then shall thou understand the fear
of the Lord,
>> and find the knowledge of God.
>> Yeah.
>> The Lord give the Lord say the fear of
the Lord is the beginning of wisdom,
right? Mhm.
>> You going to incline your ear and heed
that wisdom, that word of God. Right. Go
ahead.
>> For the Lord giveth wisdom out of his
mouth cometh knowledge and
understanding.
>> This that wisdom is the word of God to
make it plain. Okay, that that's all I
got on.
>> All right, thank you for that. Hope that
answered your question as we move on to
our next one.
>> Yes. He also asks, "How do you warm your
food on the Sabbath? And can you order
food via delivery?"
First question, how do you warm your
food on the Sabbath?
Let's go into Exodus 16
because remember the Sabbath day, Lord
should find you doing the very best that
you can do because it is a holy day.
That's the Lord's day and we should be
doing the very best. But let's see what
the Lord said back here. Exodus 16:22
and 23. Brother, go ahead.
>> And it came to pass on the sixth day,
they gathered twice as much bread, two
for one man, and all the rulers of the
congregation came and told Moses.
>> So on the sixth day, they gathered twice
as much so they wouldn't have to pollute
the Sabbath. Go ahead. And he said unto
them, "This is that which the Lord hath
said, tomorrow is the rest of the holy
Sabbath unto the Lord. So bake that
which ye will bake today, and seek that
ye will see, and that which remain
overlay it up for you to be kept until
the morning." So you supposed to either
bake what you go bake or boil what you
go boil on the sixth day so that you'll
have enough for the seventh day because
the Lord do not want you to be polluting
his Sabbath day. Verse 26.
>> Six days you shall gather it. But on the
seventh day which is the Sabbath in it
there shall be none.
>> On the sixth day you gather twice as
much. plan what you going to eat for
that seven day. You don't have to go out
and buy. You don't have to be worrying
about warming up because you're not
supposed to be using your microwave,
stove, all that kind of stuff. You
should not do that. What was the second
part of the question, Deborah?
>> Uh the second part is, can you order
food via delivery?
>> No, you shouldn't be ordering food via
delivery either. You know, you don't
want Door Dash and Uber Eats and GrubHub
showing up to your house on the Sabbath
day to deliver you food. You should be
planning that on the sixth day. And
believe you me, you can eat room
temperature food. A lot of us eat room
temperature, be it sandwiches or chicken
or something to that effect. But you can
do it. Don't act like you have to have
your food warm on the Sabbath day to eat
it. Just follow what thus says the Lord.
And that's all I got.
And we're going to move on to our next
question.
>> Next question. Sister Audrey Bud asks in
Genesis 4 verse14,
"If Adam, Eve, and their sons were the
first people, who was being talked about
that everyone that finds me shall slay
me?"
>> All right. When Cain was saying,
"Everybody that finds me shall slay me."
Brother Julius,
>> let's go to that scripture, brother
Tanzel.
Let's go to that scripture. Let's go to
Genesis chapter 4, and we're going to
read verses 1-4. And then we're going to
skip. Go ahead.
>> And Adam knew Eve, his wife, and she
conceived and bare Cain and said, "I
have gotten a man from the Lord."
>> Uhhuh. And she again bare his brother
Abel. And Abel was a keeper of sheep.
But Cain was a tiller of the ground.
>> Yes.
>> And in process of time, it came to pass
that Cain brought of the fruit of the
ground an offering unto the Lord.
>> Now I want you to underline and
highlight in process of time. Continue
to read at verse four.
>> And Abel he also brought of the first of
his flock and of the fat thereof. And
the Lord had respect unto Abel and to
his offering.
So now let's skip down. So they were
walking and uh Cain rose up and slew
Abel.
Read verse 17. Let's look at what's
going on in uh in the in process of
time. Go ahead to verse 17.
>> And Cain knew his wife and she conceived
and bear Enoch. And he built the city
and called the name of the city after
the name of his son Enoch.
>> So Cain had children too. Let's go to
Genesis the 5th chapter. Adam, Eve,
Cain, and Abel were the first, but they
were they were
they were the first people, but not the
only people. I'm going to show you what
I'm talking about. Genesis chapter 5,
verse one. Go ahead.
>> This is the book of the generation of
Adam. In the day that God created man,
and the likeness of God made he him,
male and female created he them, and
blessed him,
>> and called their name Adam, in the day
when they were created.
>> Go ahead.
>> And Adam lived 130 years, and begott a
son in his own likeness after his image,
and called his name Seth.
>> But wait a minute. But wait a minute. He
had Cain and Abel first.
Cain killed Abel, but then Adam lived
another 130 years and had Seth. And then
what happened after that? Go ahead.
>> And the days of Adam after he had
begotten Seth were 800 years. And he
begot sons and daughters.
>> So those are the people that Cain said,
"Anybody that findeth me shall slay me."
These are the rest of the sons of uh
Adam and also Cain was bearing children
also. So therefore, Adam, Eve, Cain and
Abel were the first people but not the
only people because he lived a hund
another 800 years and begat sons and
daughters.
I hope that answered your question. It
just names. It just name Cain, Abel, and
Seth, but it doesn't name the rest of
the sons and daughters.
>> I hope that helps.
>> All right, thank you for that. As we
move on to our next question,
>> next question. Time out. Houston asks,
"Is the book of Job an allegory?"
because it literally says in Job 2 verse
three that God let Satan move him
against Job and that led to his innocent
kids and servants being killed.
All right. Don't say nothing about his
kids being innocent, but just to keep
our viewers with us, allegory is a
story, a poem or picture used to explain
a point or to make a point. And so,
let's go to Job 2 and 3 and we going to
open it up to the panel because in this
case, it is a story being told.
Job 2
and read that verse three, brother, and
then we're going to open it up to the
panel.
I handle that. Read it.
>> All right.
>> The Lord said to Satan, "Has thou
considered my servant Job? For there is
none like him in the earth, a perfect
and an upright man, one that fear God
and is you with evil? And still he hold
fast his integrity, although thou movest
me against him to destroy him without a
cause."
>> That's why I wanted to read that.
You know, he said, "Move me against it."
But listen, God invited Satan to Job.
Cuz he said, "Have you considered my
servant Job?" And why did he do that?
Cuz he wanted to show Satan that a true
servant of God.
That that that he didn't have no power
over a true servant of God. But as far
as his children getting killed and and
servants getting killed, God is God. He
killed and he make a lie. And let's show
you something now. When the beast and
the false prophets ruling, you going to
have righteous people there that's
teaching their God. They're teaching the
truth. Let's go into Daniel's 11th
chapter and read verse 32-35.
And such as do wickedly against the
covenant shall he corrupt by flattery.
But the people that do know their God
shall be strong and do exploits.
And they that understand among the
people shall instruct many. Yet they
shall fall by the sword and by the flame
by captivity and by spoils many days.
Go ahead.
>> Now when they shall fall, they shall be
hoping with a little help, but many
shall cleave to them with flattery. And
some of them of understanding shall fall
to try them and to purge and to make
them white even to the time of the end
because it is yet for a time appointed.
>> Now he said some of them shall fall. Is
that correct?
>> Yeah.
to do what
to try.
>> So now you can have some people that's
talking preach going to be preaching the
gospel and telling the truth and they
are righteous and the Lord is going to
allow them to be killed some of them to
try the ones that are still living. See
if they would stand their ground like
Job stood his.
So, this is all about uh uh showing the
strength of a true servant of God. Let's
show you what God did concerning
Abraham.
Let's go into Genesis the 22nd chapter.
We're going to read one and two, then
we're going to skip.
And it came to pass after these things
that God did tempt Abraham and said unto
him, Abraham. And he said, Behold, here
I am. And he said, Take now thy son, thy
only son, Isaac, whom thou lovest, and
get thee into the land of Moriah, and
offer him therefore a burnt offering
upon one of the mountains, which I will
tell thee of.
>> Now, skip down to verse N and continue.
And they came to the place which God had
told him of. And Abraham built an altar
there, and laid the wood in order, and
bound Isaac his son, laid him on the
altar upon the wood. And Abraham
stretched forth his hand, and took the
knife to slay his son. And the angel of
the Lord called unto him out of heaven,
and said, Abraham, Abraham. And he said,
Here am I. And he said, "Lay not th hand
upon the lad, neither do thou anything
unto him. For now I know that thou
fearst God, seeing thou hast not
withheld thy son, thy only son from me."
>> Now, so Abraham was going to kill Isaac,
you know, and and then and when he was
do that, then Lord said, "Now I know
that thou fears God."
>> Why was Abraham going to kill Isaac?
because God had a power to raise him up.
And let's show you what I'm talking
about.
Let's go to Hebrews the 11th chapter,
read verses 17- 19.
By faith Abraham, when he was tried,
offered up Isaac. And he that had
received the promises, offered up his
only begotten son, of whom it was said
that in Isaac shall thy seed be called,
accounting that God was able to raise
him up, even from the dead, from whence
also he received him in a figure.
So Abraham knew if he killed Isaac, God
was just going to raise him up,
>> right?
>> In this case, the covenant was going
through him. Same thing with Job. Job
know the power of God. God, the dead
person mean nothing to God cuz he going
to raise everybody up anyway.
So now,
as far as innocent and guilty,
God's going to let a lot of the saints
be killed. That's why this false prophet
going to make war with the saints and
prevail.
But it don't mean nothing. You know why?
Because if you righteous, God going to
raise you up and you going to be in the
first resurrection
through these innocent people. You call
in these servant, God allow it
because he know he can raise them up.
That's all they have to say.
>> Yep. All of us with wisdom and knowledge
are all shooting for that first
resurrection.
All right, hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
>> Moving on. Tomorrow Williams asks, "What
is the nationality of the Babylonians
back in Daniel's time?"
>> What about these Babylonians back in
Daniel's time? and brother Julius
>> Babylon the original Babylonians were
Hammites black folks but
in 1626 BC uh 626 BC Neba Palasser the
Calan knocked out the original Babylons
so Neb let's go to Ezra the 5th chapter
and took on their took on the name of
their country but they were Gentiles
Ezra Chapter 5,
>> 1st Chronicles, 2 Chronicle. Then we
have the book of Ezras.
>> Uh-huh.
Ezra chapter 5 and just one verse,
brother. Read verse 12.
But after that our fathers had provoked
the God of heaven unto wrath, he gave
them into the hand of Nebuchadnezzar,
the king of Babylon, the Calaldian,
>> the Calans, Gentiles, Persians. Go
ahead.
>> Who destroyed this house and carried the
people away unto Babylon.
>> Now, let's go to Daniel the first
chapter. Let's pick him up again. Daniel
chapter 1.
the first gentile dynasties.
Nebuchadnezzar,
Nebuchadnezzar II, now Daniel 1
and verse one,
>> in the third year of the reign of
Jehookim, king of Judea, came
Nebuchadnezzar,
king of Babylon, unto Jerusalem, and
besieged it.
>> So the Babylonians, the original
Babylonians, but black were black or
Hammites.
Now when Nebuchadnezzar came along, they
had conquered the original Babylonians
and took over the title of king of
Babylon which was their territories. So
the original these people in Daniel days
were Gentiles. Nebuchadnezzar,
Belshazzer, all of them were Persians.
Okay? Or what we call modern day
Iranians. Gentiles. That's all I got.
All right, thank you for that. As we
move on to our next question,
>> moving on. Sam Burns says, "The Lord's
command the men to come before him three
times a year and without bias." Who is
he referring to in Ezekiel 44
6-8?
>> Three times in a year. What is Ezekiel
44 6-8 talking about, brother Dre?
>> Yeah, let's go to Ezekiel 44. Yeah, that
three times in a year, the feast of
unleaven bread, feast of weeks, and
feast of tabernacles
and without bias. Let's go to Ezekiel 44
and pick it up at verse six.
>> Go ahead, brother Tanzel, when you get
it. And thou shall say unto the
rebellious, even to the house of Israel,
thus sayeth the Lord God, oh ye house of
Israel, that it sufficees you of all
your abominations. Now you see it says,
say to the house of Israel. So you ask
the question, who is this talking about?
It's talking about Israel, but it's
talking about something that Israel has
done as well. Go ahead. and that ye have
brought into my sanctuary strangers,
uncircumcised in heart and uncircumcised
in flesh to be in my sanctuary to
pollute it even my house when ye offer
my bread and fat in the blood and they
have broken my covenant because of your
all your abomination.
So, Israel brought in strangers that are
uncircumcised
in heart and in flesh,
and they have broken the covenant
because of all of their abominations. Go
ahead, brother.
>> And you have not kept the charge of my
holy things, but you have set keepers of
my charge in my sanctuary for
yourselves.
>> Go ahead. Thus sayeth the Lord God, "No
stranger uncircumcised in heart, nor
uncircumcised in flesh shall enter into
my sanctuary, or any stranger that is
among the children of Israel."
>> So who is this talking about? It's
talking to Israel. Talking about what
Israel done and bringing in strangers
that are uncircumcised in heart and
uncircumcised in flesh. And then it goes
on to say, "Thus said the Lord, no
stranger uncircumcised in heart or
uncircumcised in flesh shall enter into
my sanctuary of any stranger that is
among the children of Israel." So those
that are to come into this sanctuary,
they must needs be circumcised as it
says in Genesis 17. Let's go to Exodus
12 right quick. Exodus 12.
Exodus 12. We're going to pick it up at
verse 43. Exodus 12 and 43. Go ahead,
brother.
>> And the Lord said unto Moses and Aaron,
this is the ordinance of the Passover.
>> No stranger eat thereof.
>> Yes.
>> But every man serving that is bought for
money, when thou hast circumcised him,
then shall he eat thereof. when thou
hast circumcised him, every servant that
is bought for money. We'll read that.
Hey, we were all bought with a price
with the precious precious blood of
Jesus.
>> Skip down to verse 48, brother. Go
ahead.
>> And when a stranger shall adjourn with
thee, and will keep the Passover to the
Lord, let all his males be circumcised.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And then let him come near and keep it.
And he shall be as one that is born in
the land. For no uncircumcised person
shall eat thereof.
One law.
>> Go ahead.
>> One law shall be to him that is homeborn
and unto the stranger that's adjourned
among him.
>> One law. So the stranger has to be
circumcised too. And this is the
ordinance of the Passover. Now last
place 1 Corinthians 5. We going to read
verse 7. 1 Corinthians 5:7. When you get
it, go ahead, brother, and read that.
Purge out therefore the old leaven that
ye may be a new lump, as ye are
unleavened. For even Christ our
Passover, is sacrificed for us.
>> And if you are partaking of the
Passover,
you must needs be circumcised. You must
be circumcised. in heart and in flesh.
And that Ezekiel 44 is talking about a
time to come. That's not just back then.
That's all I got on that.
>> Yeah. Can't get around that, Brother
Dre. By no means.
All right. Hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
>> Moving on. Nazi moure says,
"If 19 and younger are not accountable
for their sins and actions, are they all
going to have mercy?"
>> Yes, caller.
>> But the first thing is
whoever the Lord going to have mercy on,
he going to have mercy on. But the
reason we know that the Lord held them
accountable
uh from 20 it up is because what the
Lord said when he brought Israel out of
Egypt. All Israel m and complained
against God and broke his and broke his
laws. But then God did something let us
know that he held a 20 year old and
upward uh accountable.
But as far as he is talking about uh uh
uh
uh mercy, then you have to go to God for
that. But let me go and show you why we
you we you know that God hold you
accountable. Let's go into Numbers 14th
chapter.
We're going to read 22 and 24 to 24.
Then we going to skip
numbers 14:22- 24.
>> Because all those men which have seen my
glory and my miracles which I did in
Egypt and in the wilderness, and have
tempted me now these 10 times, and have
not hearkened to my voice. Surely they
shall not see the land which I swear
unto their fathers, neither shall any of
them that provoke me see it.
But my servant Caleb,
>> what verse is that?
>> That was the end of 23.
>> Go ahead.
>> But my servant Caleb, because he hath
another spirit with him, and have
followed me fully, him will I bring into
the land wherein he went, and his seed
shall possess it.
>> Okay. Now, skip down to verse 29 and
read to verse 34.
and your carcasses shall fall in this
wilderness, and all that were numbered
of you, according to your whole number,
from 20 years old and upward, which ye
have murmured against me. Doubtless ye
shall not come into the land concerning
which I swear to make you dwell therein,
save Caleb the son of Jeffina, and
Joshua the son of Nun. But your little
ones which ye said should be a prey,
them will I bring in, and they shall
know the land which ye have despised.
But as for you, your carcasses, they
shall fall in this wilderness, and your
children shall wander in the wilderness
40 years, and bear your hoarder until
your carcasses be wasted in the
wilderness.
>> What verse was that?
>> That was in 33.
Go ahead. Read 34.
>> After the number of the days in which ye
scattered the land, search the land even
40 days, each day for a year shall ye
bear your iniquities. Even 40 years, and
ye shall know my preach of promise.
>> Now he said, for 20 years and upward.
Now skip down. Let's go to Deuteronomy
uh chapter one and read verse 39.
your little ones which he said shall be
a prey, and your children which in that
day had no knowledge between good and
evil, they shall go in thither, and unto
them will I give it, they shall possess
it.
So now according to what we read, he
said, "Your little ones that had no
knowledge of good and evil, they going
to possess the land." Those are the ones
from 19 and backwards. Uh uh uh and and
and and backwards. But the ones from 20
years and older, he said was not going
to be in the land. So now what mercy God
have, you have to go to God for that. We
just telling you that this tell us that
God hold you respon hold you responsible
when you're 20 years and older.
That's why we don't baptize anybody
under 20 years old because when you're
baptizing you entered into a blood
covenant
which is the new covenant.
That's all I have to say.
Hope that answered your question, Sister
Deborah, as we move on with our next
>> next question. Time out. Houston says,
"Will people in heaven
be able to see their loved ones in the
lake of fire? And does God wipe their
memories so they won't care anymore?
All right, first part of that question,
John 3:13. Brother Julius already read
that no man has ascended under heaven.
But um let's open it up to the panel
about they want to knowing does God wipe
the memories
so they won't care anymore about your
loved ones in the lake of fire?
>> I have guest call
ain't nobody going to heaven. We read
earlier about the but uh God is going to
bring the kingdom to you in 21st chapter
of revelation
and also in the first chapter of Luke it
tell you that Jesus going to come and
sit on David's throne.
>> They tell you also I'm just quoting some
scripture before we get through reading.
They tell you also when when Jesus in
the second Thessalonians the 4th chapter
that Jesus going to descend from heaven
and the dead going to be raised and the
living changed they going to meet him in
the air
and Zechariah the 14th chapter they that
the Lord's going to come and in that day
with all his saints with him those one
that met him in the air and his feet
going to stand on Mount Olive which is
east of Jerusalem on this earth ain't
nobody going to heaven.
But
when the kingdom come here and during
the thousand year millennium to when
Jesus have his kingdom on this earth,
yes, you will be able to see whoever it
is in a lake of fire. Even communicate
with him. Let's go into lake to Luke the
16th chapter.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And read verse 22 and 26 uh to 26. This
is between Lazarus and the rich man
and it and involves Abraham.
So that tells me this is after the last
resurrection.
And it came to pass that the beggar died
and was carried by the angels into
Abraham's bosom. The rich man also died
and was buried. And in hell he lifted up
his eyes being in torments and see if
Abraham a far off and Lazarus in his
bosom. And he cried and said, "Father
Abraham, have mercy on me." And he sent
Lazarus that he may dip the tip of his
finger in water and cool my tongue, for
I am tormented in this flame.
But Abraham said, "Son, remember that
thou in that lifetime receiveth that
good things, and likewise Lazarus evil
things, but now he is comforted, and
thou are tormented. Besides all this,
between us and you there is a great g,
so that they which would pass from hence
to you cannot, neither can they pass to
us that will come from vents.
So now both of them going to be in the
kingdom of Jesus and in the kingdom of
father. Not only will they see one
another and know one another, they will
be able to communicate.
And all this is going to take place on
earth.
Nothing takes place in heaven. Let's go
into Isaiah the 66th chapter.
We're going to read verse 15 first and
then we're going to skip down and read
verse 23 and 24.
>> Isaiah 6 Isaiah Isaiah 66
>> and 15 verse.
But behold, the Lord will come with fire
and with his terror like a whirlwind to
render his anger with fury and his
rebuke with flames of fire.
>> Now this is the coming of Jesus. Now
skip down to verse 23. Let me show you
what's going to happen. Read 23 and 24.
And it shall come to pass that from one
new moon to another, and from one
Sabbath to another shall all flesh come
to worship before me, said the Lord. And
they shall go forth and look upon the
car.
>> Look, they going to come to worship him
cuz he and that's going to be in
Jerusalem on this earth. Now, when they
come, let's see what they going to do.
Keep continue on. and they shall go
forth and look upon the carcasses of the
men that have transgressed against me,
>> for their worms shall not die, neither
shall their fire be quenched, and they
shall be in a horror unto all flesh.
>> So yeah, you going to be able to look at
your loved one. They going to know you,
you going to know them. They will be
able to talk to you and you will be able
to talk to them. But the fix is in
like Jesus says a g between you and
them. You can't go there. It can't come
to you. But all of this is on the earth.
Not nothing is in heaven because even
except for the father and his angel at
that time. But then at the end of the
thousand-year rule of Jesus, then the
father and his angels going to leave
heaven.
So yeah, you'll be able to see him and
communicate with him. That's all I have
to say.
>> All right. Thank you for that, Sister
Deborah. I believe the time check. We're
going into news territory.
>> Yes, the time is 8:50. We are now into
tonight's Q&A for Wednesday, July the
30th of 2025.
Jaquila Au jobi asks, "Is Jesus God?" In
many conversations I have with other
believers, they always mention the
Trinity.
>> All right, let's open these questions up
for the panel. The first one asks, "Is
is Jesus God?"
>> Absolutely.
>> Absolutely. Let's go to 1 Timothy the 3r
chapter verse 16.
1 Timothy 3
verse 16. And I'm going to tie that with
the uh St. John.
When you get it, go ahead and read.
>> And without controversy, great is the
mystery of godliness. God was manifested
in the flesh, justified in the spirit,
seen of angels, preached into the
Gentiles, believe on in the world,
receive up into glory.
>> Yeah. Because ain't nobody went up into
glory, which is the heaven they was
talking about earlier, but the one that
came down, and that was Jesus. So, yeah,
Jesus, God. Go to St. John chapter 20.
when he resurrected on the third day,
he went to go visit his uh apostles.
Okay.
St. John 20, read verse 28 to I'm sorry,
read verse 26- 28.
>> And after 8 days again his disciples
were within and Thomas with them. Then
came Jesus, the doors being shut, stood
in the midst, and said, "Peace be unto
you."
But then said he to Thomas, "Reach
hither thy finger, and behold my hands,
and reach hither thy hands, and thrust
it into my side. Be not faithless, but
believing."
>> And Thomas answered and said unto him,
My Lord and my God,
>> believe in God. and Thomas let you know
it. Yeah. Jesus God.
>> And there's a lot more verses we can go
to, but that's all I got.
>> Yep. And we can go to that uh
Philippians 2. Let's go there.
Philippians 2. And there was some good
ones, Jerome. Let's go there.
Philippians 2 and let's just read two
verses. Verse five and six. When you get
there.
>> But let this mind be in you which also
in Christ Jesus.
who being in the form of God and thought
in that robbery to be equal with God.
>> All right. Anybody else?
>> Thomas said, "My Lord and my God."
>> My Lord and my God. Yep.
>> But let's go into Hebrews the first
chapter and show you what God called him
God.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Hebrews 1.
>> Go ahead.
Hebrews 1 and1
>> um
8.
>> Yeah.
>> But unto the Son he saith, thy throne,
oh God, is forever and ever. A setter of
righteousness is the scepter of thy
kingdom.
>> Go ahead.
>> Thou hast loved righteousness and hated
iniquity. Therefore God, even thy God
have anointed thee with the oil of
gladness above thy fellows.
>> Now if God call him God, then who can
say he is not God?
>> Nobody.
>> The other part for the other part you
say is a trinity. There is no such thing
as a trinity.
>> Go in the first five and seven because
this because they answer about trinity
too. Isn't that correct? Yes.
>> Five and go to St. John 5 and 7 and
let's see where he get that from.
>> St. John 5
and verse
7.
St. John 5 and 7. The impotent man
answered him, "Sir, I have no man when
the water is troubled to put me in
I said first John.
>> Okay.
The body.
For there are three that bear record in
heaven, the Father, the Word, and the
Holy Ghost. And these three are one.
>> Okay, they bear record. Skip down and
read verse 10.
He that believeth on the son of God hath
the witness in himself. But he that
believeth not God hath made him a liar
because he believeth not the record that
God gave of his son.
>> And this
now that's that's he believed not the
record that God gave him his son. So
let's go and look at this three that
bear record. Go to Revelation the first
chapter.
Read verses one and two.
>> The revelation of Jesus Christ, which
God gave unto him.
>> That's one, right? Go ahead.
>> That's right. To show unto his servants
things which must shortly come to pass.
>> Revelation of Jesus Christ,
>> which God gave unto him. Jesus is one.
He is God and and the and God the Father
is one. And he want to show unto his
servant John. And what did he use? Go
ahead.
>> And he sent and signified it by his
angel
unto his servant John.
>> Now, so you had God the Father, you have
God the Son, but the angel is a
meditating spirit. It ain't never been
but
why don't play St. John 1 and start
reading at verse one.
In the beginning was the word and the
word was with God and the word was God.
>> Reading it.
>> Keep going.
>> Yeah.
>> And the same was in
the same was in the beginning with God.
All things were made by him and without
him was not anything made that was made.
>> Now skip down I think it's verse 9 or 10
where he said he was in the world.
>> Verse 10 he was in the world and the
world was made by him and the world knew
him not.
>> Now so now you notice it didn't me
mention but two in the beginning was the
word. The word were with God and the
word was God. There's only been two
that's a part of the Godhead. There
ain't never been three. The third one
that they say God the Holy Ghost is an
angel and he is not God. That's all
answers say.
>> Yeah. All right, Sister Deborah. Our
next question is time is a ticking when
you're having fun.
>> Yes. Big Brad asks, "Is smoking
marijuana detestable to God or si?"
Guess caller.
>> Sin is the transgression of the law.
>> Yes.
>> Go and read it. What's that verse?
What's that? Uh 1 John 5 and 7.
>> 1 John 3 and 4.
>> Yeah. Three and four.
This the biblical definition of sin.
>> Whosoever committh sin transgressth also
the law. For sin is the transgression of
the law.
Now you go and find out what the law is.
Then you find out what sin is.
>> Yep.
>> That's all say.
>> All right. Stay tuned with us. We will
teach you that law.
>> All right. Sister Deb, let's go to our
final question of the evening.
>> All right. Pauline R asks in Matthew 12
43- 45. Can you share light on this? Do
unclean spirits come in if you don't
read the word daily?
>> Matthew 12.
And you said 43- 45.
>> Yes.
>> All right. Let's read that. Tanzel, our
last question of the evening.
When the unclean spirit is gone out of a
man, he walketh through dry places,
seeking rest, and findeth none.
Then he said, I will return to my house
from whence I came out.
>> And when he is come, he findeth it
empty, swept in, and garnished.
Then goeth he and taketh with himself e
seven other spirits more wicked than
himself.
And they enter in and dwell there. And
the last state of that man is worse than
the first. Even so shall it be also unto
this wicked generation.
>> Let's open that up to the panel with the
question again. De
>> Yes. The question is they want some uh
shed some light on Matthew 12
43- 45. And then they ask if uh do
unclean spirits come in if you don't
read the word daily.
>> Guest caller.
>> No.
>> All I have to say.
>> Yeah. But read your word daily. Always a
good thing to do.
>> All right.
>> And brother, let me let me make a
statement uh for the previous question
that was asked about about children 19
uh and and and under guest calls
answered the question. But the bottom
line is when the when the person asks a
question are are 19 years old
responsible. It it also depends. The
script the commandment says train up a
child in the way that they should go.
And if that child is dis is disrespected
to elders or or or disobedient to their
parents like guest caller said like we
can read the Lord will have mercy whom
he will. But on your own read uh 2 Kings
the 2 chapter when those little children
mocked Elicia the prophet and the Lord
sent 42 she uh uh uh sent two she bears
and killed 42 children
for their disrespecting. So train up a
child in the way this should go
>> right.
Okay, and we have ran out of time and we
want to thank everybody from all around
the world who joined us this evening.
Want to say thank you and if you
submitted a question we didn't get to
it, please don't resubmit it. Sister
Deborah, take it put it in rotation and
that question will be dealt with next
Wednesday. So until we all come together
again, please be safe out there. Be
blessed. Stay prayed up as Brother
Tanzel closes us out. Our
Father, which are in heaven, hallowed be
thy name. Thy kingdom come, thy will be
done in earth as it is in heaven. Give
us this day our daily bread, and forgive
us of our debts as we forgive our
debtors, and lead us not into
temptation, but deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom and the power
and the glory forever.